<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>nlp - Category -</title><link>/categories/nlp/</link><description>nlp - Category -</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/nlp/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Deepfake Audio with Wav2Lip</title><link>/deepfake-audio-with-wav2lip/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Chiawei Lim</author><guid>/deepfake-audio-with-wav2lip/</guid><description>Overview of Deepfake Technology Deepfake is a technology that creates synthesis media with a subfield of Machine Learning - Deep Learning.
Photo by the author A common use case that the public is aware of is the application of face-swapping. A target face is swapped and merged, often seamlessly on first glance view, to create an altered event.
Photo by the author On a high level, Deepfake can be split into 3 sub-domains based on the focus of the media to alter.</description></item><item><title>Speech-to-Text Demo Trained on Conversational Speech</title><link>/speech-to-text-demo/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Chiawei Lim</author><guid>/speech-to-text-demo/</guid><description>Huggingface Space Quick Demo of speech-to-text model trained with wav2vec2-conformer
Try the model with
Examples provided Upload audio files with extension .wav/.mp3/.flac Recordings through microphone Photo by the author Note Detailed notes about the data preparation, model training and serving will be elaborated.</description></item><item><title>Understand Audio Data with Computer Vision Background</title><link>/understand-audio-data-with-computer-vision-background/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Chiawei Lim</author><guid>/understand-audio-data-with-computer-vision-background/</guid><description>&lt;p>Side by side comparison of audio and visual data for quick understanding.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr></description></item><item><title>Youtube to Text with Speech Recognition in Python</title><link>/youtube-to-text-with-speech-recognition-in-python/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Chiawei Lim</author><guid>/youtube-to-text-with-speech-recognition-in-python/</guid><description>&lt;p>Python-based libraries to download Youtube videos for NLP use cases&lt;/p>
&lt;hr></description></item></channel></rss>